<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id='supporting_definition_standardisation_committee_for_care_information.description'>
  <title>Description</title>
  <titlealts>
    <searchtitle>Supporting Information: Standardisation Committee for Care Information - Description</searchtitle>
  </titlealts>
  <body>
  <div>
    <p>
      <b>
The 
                <xref outputclass="supportingInformation" keyref="supporting_definition_standardisation_committee_for_care_information">Standardisation Committee for Care Information</xref>
 (<xref outputclass="supportingInformation" keyref="supporting_definition_standardisation_committee_for_care_information">SCCI</xref>) closed on 31 March 2017.            </b>
    </p>
    <p>
      <b>
Responsibility for the approval of Information Standards has transferred to the 
                <xref outputclass="businessDefinition" keyref="business_definition_data_coordination_board">Data Coordination Board</xref>
 (<xref outputclass="businessDefinition" keyref="business_definition_data_coordination_board">DCB</xref>).            </b>
    </p>
    <p>
      <b>
The following definition will remain in the NHS Data Model and Dictionary as it is relevant for Information Standards that were assured and approved by the 
                <xref outputclass="supportingInformation" keyref="supporting_definition_standardisation_committee_for_care_information">Standardisation Committee for Care Information</xref>
 between 1 April 2014 and 31 March 2017.            </b>
    </p>
    <p>The Standardisation Committee for Care Information replaced the Information Standards Board for Health and Social Care (ISB) on 1 April 2014.</p>
The Standardisation Committee for Care Information: 
        <ul>
      <li>
        <div>has delegated authority from the National Information Board (NIB) to accept Information Standards and Collections (including Extractions) (ISCEs) for health and social care</div>
      </li>
      <li>
        <div>is responsible for the need to change, deprecate and retire existing approved Information Standards and Collections (including Extractions) Notices</div>
      </li>
      <li>
        <div>takes its membership from a wide range of national bodies and Organisations involved in the provision and management of health and social care services in England. This ensures a system-wide, joined-up approach to decision-making</div>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
For further information on the Standardisation Committee for Care Information, see the NHS Digital website at: 
            <xref href="https://digital.nhs.uk/isce" scope="external" format="html">Information Standards and Collections (Including Extractions) - National Governance</xref>.        </p>
  </div>
</body>
</topic>