<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id='element_socio-economic_classification_code__stop_smoking_.permitted_codes'>
  <title>Permitted Codes</title>
  <titlealts>
    <searchtitle>Data Element: SOCIO-ECONOMIC CLASSIFICATION CODE (STOP SMOKING) - Permitted Codes</searchtitle>
  </titlealts>
  <body>
    <simpletable relcolwidth='1* 4*' outputclass='table table-striped table-sm'>
      <sthead outputclass='thead-light'>
        <stentry>Code</stentry>
        <stentry>Description</stentry>
      </sthead>
      <strow>
        <stentry>01</stentry>
        <stentry>Full-time Student</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>02</stentry>
        <stentry>Never worked or unemployed for over one year. If unemployed for less than one year, last known occupation should be used for classification.</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>03</stentry>
        <stentry>Retired</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>04</stentry>
        <stentry>Home carer i.e. looking after children, family or home</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>05</stentry>
        <stentry>Sick or disabled and unable to work</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>06</stentry>
        <stentry>Managerial/ professional. Examples include: accountant, artist, civil/mechanical engineer, medical practitioner, musician, nurse, police officer (sergeant or above), physiotherapist, scientist, social worker, software engineer, solicitor, teacher, welfare officer. Those usually responsible for planning, organising and co-ordinating work for finance</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>07</stentry>
        <stentry>Intermediate. Examples include: call centre agent, clerical worker, nursery auxiliary, office clerk, secretary</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>08</stentry>
        <stentry>Routine and manual (self employed should not be included in this category). Examples include: electrician, fitter, gardener, inspector, plumber, printer, train driver, tool maker, bar staff, caretaker, catering assistant, cleaner, farm worker, HGV driver, labourer, machine operative, messenger, packer, porter, postal worker, receptionist, sales assistant, security guard, sewing machinist, van driver, waiter/waitress</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>09</stentry>
        <stentry>Prisoner</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>96</stentry>
        <stentry>Other (not listed)</stentry>
      </strow>
    </simpletable>
  </body>
</topic>