<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id='element_ward_security_level.permitted_codes'>
  <title>Permitted Codes</title>
  <titlealts>
    <searchtitle>Data Element: WARD SECURITY LEVEL - Permitted Codes</searchtitle>
  </titlealts>
  <body>
    <simpletable relcolwidth='1* 4*' outputclass='table table-striped table-sm'>
      <sthead outputclass='thead-light'>
        <stentry>Code</stentry>
        <stentry>Description</stentry>
      </sthead>
      <strow>
        <stentry>
  <p>0</p>
</stentry>
        <stentry>
  <b>General (non-secure)</b>
  <p> 
</p>
  <p>
Non secure accommodation or accommodation that only has normal levels of security such as general 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_ward">WARDS</xref>
  </p>
</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>
  <p>1</p>
</stentry>
        <stentry>
  <b>Low Secure
</b>
  <p>
 Low secure 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_ward">WARDS</xref>/units deliver comprehensive, multidisciplinary, treatment and care by qualified staff for 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_patient">PATIENTS</xref>
 who demonstrate disturbed behaviour in the context of a serious mental disorder and who require the provision of security. This includes (but is not limited to) Psychiatric Intensive Care Unit (PICU), low secure forensic services, challenging behaviour services, and secure rehabilitation services.    </p>
</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>
  <p>2</p>
</stentry>
        <stentry>
  <b>Medium Secure</b>
  <p>
Medium secure 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_ward">WARDS</xref>/units deliver comprehensive, multidisciplinary treatment and care by qualified staff for 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_patient">PATIENTS</xref>
 who demonstrate disturbed behaviour in the context of a serious mental disorder and who may present a serious risk to others.    </p>
</stentry>
      </strow>
      <strow>
        <stentry>
  <p>3</p>
</stentry>
        <stentry>
  <b>High Secure
</b>
  <p>
 High secure 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_ward">WARDS</xref>/hospitals provide comprehensive, multidisciplinary treatment and care by qualified staff for 
        <xref outputclass="class" keyref="class_patient">PATIENTS</xref>
 who demonstrate disturbed behaviour in the context of a serious mental disorder and have been assessed as presenting a grave and immediate danger to others.  The Hospital must be part of an 
        <xref outputclass="businessDefinition" keyref="business_definition_nhs_trust">NHS Trust</xref>
 approved by the Secretary of State to provide high security psychiatric services.    </p>
</stentry>
      </strow>
    </simpletable>
  </body>
</topic>